Jack Fischer

💻 Full-Stack Web Developer. 📤 Occasional Adventurer. 🌊 Big Fan of Garlic Naan.

Address: Remote/Miami Beach, FL | Email: letsbuild@jackbuildstech.com

Personal Site: https://jackbuildstech.com | GitHub: https://github.com/sunspla-sh

Summary

I enjoy growing and scaling web applications, and I bring a passion for learning, education, and continuous growth to any team that I'm a part of. Additionally, I have a knack for patiently and repeatedly explaining features, functionality, and concepts with no loss of enthusiasm to absolutely anyone, technical or non-technical.

Visit my personal site https://jackbuildstech.com for a summary of my projects and experience or watch my video resume: https://youtu.be/ERXwTo-zWig

Experience

Full Stack Web Development Instructor (Contractor) Ironhack (https://ironhack.com)

Mar 2022 - Jan 2023

- My former students collectively earn roughly \$800,000-1,000,000 in annual income as junior web developers (or similar tech jobs) with an average salary in the \$50,000-60,000 range (representing a 50-100% increase in annual income for most of them, because they primarily came from a hospitality or retail service background)
- Taught 4 cohorts of students to use modern, full stack web development technologies such as the following: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, Express, Handlebars, Databases (MongoDB), ODMs (Mongoose), Single-page Applications (React), Version Control (Git and Github), Unit Testing (Jest), Deployment, etc.

Founder/Full Stack Web Developer Failed Startups

Aug 2020 - Feb 2022

- Rejected from YCombinator (a startup accelerator) with first startup in the geothermal industry. It was capital-intensive and we had no clear path forward (and no cash), so my co-founders returned to their jobs.
- Continued on solo with a second startup scuba diving booking software-as-a-service. I tried to be smarter this time and build something that required no starting investment. I attempted to pre-sell based on UX/UI wireframes before coding it and found some interested users, but failed to get product-market fit before I ran out of savings.

Carnival Cruise Line (https://carnival.com)

- Built various front end sections of the carnival.com site including updated versions of the checkout review page within the booking engine, mobile menu, modals, banners, sliders etc
- A/B tested code and toggled features using Optimizely to verify that newly coded sections of the site increased overall customer conversions/revenue
- Hired and managed 4 employees/subcontractors doing frontend web development, UX/UI design, and data analytics, who were billed under me and worked alongside me at Carnival

Projects (Practice & Personal)

1) JobAppTrack.com (Web Application and Chrome Extension)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/simple-job-app-tracker-react)
Technologies Used:

Docker, Vite, React, CSS, JavaScript, Prisma, SQLite, Node.js, Express, Nodemailer, Handlebars, Open Graph Protocol, CRXJS, pnpm, TurboRepo, Socket.io (Websockets), Fly.io

2) GitBoxDraw.com (Web Application)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/github-commit-text-generator)

Technologies Used:

Vite, Sass, HTML, JavaScript, Open Graph Protocol, Node.js, Rollup, JavaScript Obfuscator (Rollup Plugin), npm, DigitalOcean

3) IPomg.com (Web Application)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/ipomg-static)

Technologies Used:

Vite, TailwindCSS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MaxMind GeoLite2 DB, Node.js, Express, npm, DigitalOcean

Other practice/personal projects can be seen on GitHub at aithub.com/sunspla-sh

Tech Skills and Theory

Front-End Web Development

TypeScript, JavaScript, Single-page Applications (React), GraphQL, HTML, CSS, SASS, TailwindCSS, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, D3, Vite, Chrome Extensions (CRXJS), npm, pnpm, Open Graph Protocol, Websockets (Socket.io)

Back-End Web Development

Node.js, Web Application Frameworks and APIs (Express.js, Nest.js), Databases (MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite), ODMs and ORMs (Mongoose, Sequelize, Prisma), GraphQL, Unit Testing (Jest), Puppeteer, Nodemailer, Email & View Templating (Handlebars), Websockets (Socket.io), MVC architecture, npm, pnpm, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, JSON, XML

DevOps and Tooling

Version Control (Git), CI/CD (TravisCI), Cloud Infrastructure (DigitalOcean, AWS, Fly.io, Heroku), Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Monorepos, Bundlers and Build Systems (TurboRepo, Rollup), Postman

Other Skills

Languages:

English (Native),
Spanish (CEFR - Level B1 - SIELE - <u>Credential ID li3knEHpdbkjrFuagvJ7RA==</u>),
Russian (CEFR - Level A2)

Video and Image Editing:

Kdenlive (Video Editing), OBS (Video recording and livestreaming) GIMP (Image Editing)

Education

Spanish (CEFR Level B1) - SIELE

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

I independently studied Spanish in Playa Del Carmen, Mexico to a tested level of CEFR Level B1 - Intermediate through the SIELE exam. CEFR Level B1 is high enough to gain entrance to some universities in Spain for a fully Spanish curriculum (no classes taught in English) such as Universidad Complutense Madrid while others require B2. My Spanish exam credential can be independently verified at the following website - https://siele.org/en/comprobar-certificado - using my credential ID: <a href="li3knEHpdbkjrFuagyJ7RA=="li3knEHpdkkjrFuagyJ7RA=="li3knEHpdkkjrFuagyJ7R

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp - Ironhack

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

10-week intensive (400+ hour) web development boot camp which complimented my existing computer science skills from some of my university classes

Russian (CEFR Level A2) - Moscow State University

May 2016 - Aug 2016

I like learning languages. I studied Russian language and culture at Lomonosov Moscow State University during a summer abroad and also visited various cities in Russia.

Liberal Studies, B.A. - Iowa State University

Aug 2014 - Aug 2018

I should have been focused on building technical skills instead of "following my passion" and taking a bunch of random liberal arts classes. Fortunately, younger me decided to fill some elective classes with computer science subjects, which led to my current career.